Guide to the Evening Star Newspaper Co. Records 1911-1972 (bulk 1911-1943, 1966-1972) MS 3009-RG 60
New-York Historical Society
Evening Star Newspaper Co. Records
1911-1972 (bulk 1911-1943, 1966-1972)
New-York Historical Society
Evening Star Newspaper Co.
MS 3009-RG 60
4 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
The Evening Star Newspaper Co. was the publisher of the Washington, D.C. daily newspaper The Evening Star. Founded in 1852, the newspaper held several names during its existence. Time Inc. purchased the newspaper in 1978 when it was known as The Washington Star. This collection contains company records from prior to Time Inc.'s acquisition including staff newsletters, a handwritten record of births of children to employees, and accounting books.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
The materials within the Evening Star Newspaper Co. Records record group are organized into three series: Series I. Newsletters; Series II. Baby Birth Record; and Series III. Accounting Books.
Historical Note
The Evening Star Newspaper Co. was the publisher of the Washington, D.C. daily newspaper The Evening Star. Founded in 1852, the newspaper held several names during its existence such as The Daily Evening Star, The Washington Daily News, and finally The Washington Star. In 1978, Time Inc. purchased The Washington Star. The newspaper declared bankruptcy in 1981.
Citations:
About Daily evening star. [volume] (Washington [D.C.]) 1852-1854. https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045461/
About Evening star. [volume] (Washington, D.C.) 1854-1972. https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/
About The Washington daily news. [volume] (Washington, D.C.) 1921-1972. https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016181/
About Washington star. [volume] (Washington, D.C.) 1975-1981. https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn79002331/
Custodial History
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Records on Washington Star finances after Time Inc.'s acquisition are in the Time Inc. Time-Life News Service Records (MS 3009-RG 14).
Scope and Contents
The collections consists of records from The Evening Star Newspaper Co. which were probably acquired by Time Inc. when it purchased The Washington Star newspaper. Records include copies of The Family Star newsletter circulated among employees of the paper, a book with handwritten records of the births of children to newspaper staff, and accounting books for the newspaper.
Account books.; American newspapers; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York; Journals (accounts); Ledgers (account books).; Newsletters.; Newspaper publishing -- United States; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York; Time, inc.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. Newsletters, 1966-1972; 1.9 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of issues of The Family Star, a newsletter sent by mail to employees of The Evening Star reporting news on happenings within the company such as hiring, retirements, and marriages of employees.
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged in chronological order.
  - The Family Star: October/November, 1966 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 1)
  - The Family Star: May/June/July, 1967 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 2)
  - The Family Star: November, 1967 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 3)
  - The Family Star: December, 1967 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 4)
  - The Family Star: January, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 5)
  - The Family Star: February, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 6)
  - The Family Star: August, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 7)
  - The Family Star: October, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 8)
  - The Family Star: November, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 9)
  - The Family Star: December, 1968 (Offsite-box 4287, Folder 10)
  - The Family Star: January, 1969 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 1)
  - The Family Star: February, 1969 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 2)
  - The Family Star: November, 1969 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 3)
  - The Family Star: December/January, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 4)
  - The Family Star: February/March, 1970 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 5)
  - The Family Star: Spring, 1970 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 6)
  - The Family Star: Autumn, 1970 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 7)
  - The Family Star: Summer, 1972 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 8)
- Series II. Baby Birth Record, 1959-1968; 0.1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  Series II consists of a custom notebook with handwritten notations on the births of children to employees of the Evening Star Newspaper Co.
  Series II is a single item.
  - The Evening Star Baby Book, 1959-1968 (Offsite-box 4288, Folder 9)
- Series III. Accounting Books, 1911-1943
  Series III consists of accounting journals and ledgers for the Evening Star Newspaper Co.
  Series III is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Journal Number 1, 1911-1916 (Offsite-box 4289, Folder 1)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Journal Number 2, 1917-1921 (Offsite-box 4289, Folder 2)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Journal Number 3, 1922-1930 (Offsite-box 4289, Folder 3)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Journal Number 4, 1931-1937 (Offsite-box 4289, Folder 4)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Journal Number 5, 1938-1943 (Offsite-box 4290, Folder 1)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Ledger Number 1, 1911-1917 (Offsite-box 4290, Folder 2)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Ledger Number 2, 1918-1920 (Offsite-box 4290, Folder 3)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Ledger Number 3, 1921-1925 (Offsite-box 4291, Folder 1)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Ledger Number 4, 1926-1930 (Offsite-box 4291, Folder 2)
  - Evening Star Newspaper Co. General Ledger Number 5, 1931-1935 (Offsite-box 4291, Folder 3)